Finding Aid for the Peter H. Prince Papers MS.2921
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
- Research Files, 1770-2006; I
  - Buncombe, Haywood, Macon, Jackson, and Swain Counties, North Carolina, 1945-2006 (bulk 1900-2006); F
    - Bradley Town: Indian Gap (5376'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - Bradley Town: Timber Top Lodge (5364'), 1958-2005 (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - Bradley Town: Charles A. Webb, 1949-1996 (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - Bradley Town: Mount Weaver (5200'), 1938-1941, 2000-2005 (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - Newfound Gap: Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - Newfound Gap: Newfound Gap Road, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - Newfound Gap: Dicus Brothers Construction Company, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - Newfound Gap: Newfound Gap Road, 1932, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - Newfound Gap: Newfound Road Gap (Tennessee Side), 1986 (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - Appalachian Trail: Appalachian Trail, 1931, 1986-2005; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 64, Folder 10] (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - Appalachian Trail: Benton MacKaye Trail, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - Appalachian Trail: Benton MacKaye's Appalachian Trail, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 87)
    - Appalachian Trail: Porter's Gap (5400'), 1945-2004 (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - Appalachian Trail: Mingo Falls (120'), 1994-2003 (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - Appalachian Trail: Southern Appalachian National Park, 1899-1904, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - Mount Ambler, NC (6130'), 1900-2000 (Box 21, Folder 91)
    - Mount Kephart (6217'), 1934-1953, 1988-2005 (Box 21, Folder 92)
    - Peak's Peak (now Mount Kephart), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - Wildcat Bounty, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 94)
    - Mount Oconoa (6217'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 95)
    - Masa Knob (5584'), 1933-2003 (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - Charlie's Bunion (5376'), 1945-2005 (Box 21, Folder 97)
    - Dry Sluice Gap (5380'), 1937, 1988-1993 (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - Top of Richland Ridge (5381'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - The Sawteeth (5450'), undated (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - Thermo Knob (6120'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 101)
    - Rhinehardt Gap (now False Gap) (5233'), 1937-1945 (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - False Gap (5233'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - John Gray Blount, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 104)
    - Love Speculation Lands, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 105)
    - Laurel Top (5907'), 1937 (Box 21, Folder 106)
    - John Gray Blount Corner (5720'), 1914, 1993-2000 (Box 21, Folder 107)
    - Peck's Corner, 1937-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Tricorner Knob (6400'), 1937, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Mount Hardison (6134'), 1930-1935, 1993-2005 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Thunderknob (now Peck's Peak) (5850'), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Three Brothers (now Mount Sequoyah) (5945'), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Sequoyah (1770-1843), undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Mount Alexander (now Mount Chapman) (6425'), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Luftee Knob (6234'), 1935-1996 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Mount Sequoyah (5945'), 1931-2005 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Haywood County, NC, 1860 Census, undated; [Transcription] (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Haywood County, NC (est. 1808), 1977-2000; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 64, Folder 11] (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Black Camp Gap, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Black Camp Gap CCC Camp NP17, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - William Mitchell Sutton, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Haywood County Board of Education Deed Index, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - 1820 US Census, Haywood County, NC, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Waynesville, NC (Haywood County Seat), 1977-1994 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Pleas and Quarter Sessions of 1810 (Haywood County), 1966, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Catloochee: Elk Returned to Great Smoky Mountains (2 February 2001), 2004 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Catloochee: Big Cataloochee, NC, 1914-1994 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Catloochee: Cataloochee Township, 1914-1999; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 65 Folder 1] (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Catloochee: Pigeon River, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Catloochee: Gadilusti, 1983-1993 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Catloochee: Mount Guyot (6621'), 1929-2005 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Catloochee: Arnold Guyot, 1934-2005 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Catloochee: Mount Yonaguska, 1932-1993 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Catloochee: Old Black (6370'), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Catloochee: Mount Henry (now Old Black) (6370'), 1937 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Catloochee: Hells Ridge, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Catloochee: Inadu Knob (5941'), 1968 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Catloochee: Black Camp Gap (4496'), 1968 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Catloochee: Ravensford Lumber Company Railroad, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Catloochee: Polls Gap (5128'), 1968, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Catloochee: Poll Gap Lumber Camp, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Catloochee: Cataloochee Balsam (5970'), undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Catloochee: Chiltoes Mountain (5888'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Catloochee: Spruce Mountain Tower and Railroad Camp (5647'), undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Catloochee: Ledge Bald (5184'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Catloochee: Pin Oak Gap (4423'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Catloochee: Balsam Corner (6020'), 1945-1983 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Catloochee: Big Cataloochee Mountain (6155'), 1935 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Catloochee: Garrett's Gap (5173'), 1968 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Catloochee: Maggot Spring Gap (5200'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Catloochee: Hemphill Bald (5573'), 1935-1983 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Tennessee Mountain Turnpike, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: George Palmer Family, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Civil War, 1914-2004 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee, 1996-2005 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Jonathan Woody Family, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: George Palmer, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: James Colwell Family, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Evan Hannah Family, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Levi B. Caldwell Cabin, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Young Bennett Family, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Jarvis Palmer House, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: High Sheriff William A. Palmer (1910-1914), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee Post Office, 1903-1916, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee Township Post Offices, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Zack White Murders Deputy, 1940-1983 (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Union Army Slaughters Cataloochee Residents, 1977-1991 (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Creighton Bennett Home Burned (1861), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: J. Clark Carrell, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Bob Forester Freezes to Death (1915), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Ben Hannah Murdered, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Palmer Chapel Methodist (est. 1898), 1898, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Big Cataloochee Methodist Episcopal Church (est. 1841), 1898-1899, 1983-1990 (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Hiram J. Caldwell, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Tom King Shooting Ends Revival, 1983-1987 (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee Log School (1892-1902), 1907, 1983-1989 (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee School Burning (1907), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 70)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Beech Grove School (1908-1944), 1907-1983 (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Hiram J. Caldwell House, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Palmer Creek (formerly Indian Creek), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Hoglen Gap (4000'), undated (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Messer Fork, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Rudolph Caldwell Murdered (1905), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 76)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Flu Epidemic (1920), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Champion Lumber Company Railroad, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: The Balsam Mountains, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - Cataloochee First Settlers: Cataloochee Precinct, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - Nellie: Nellie, NC Post Office, 1907-2000 (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - Nellie: James P. Jarrett (First Store Owner), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - Nellie: Dr. Collins Howell Grist Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - Nellie: William Messer Overshot Mill, 1983, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 84)
    - Nellie: Jesse Palmer Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 85)
    - Nellie: John Mull Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 86)
    - Nellie: John Davidson Corncracker Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 87)
    - Nellie: Tom Palmer Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - Nellie: John A. Caldwell Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 89)
    - Nellie: Charles Jarrett Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 90)
    - Nellie: Jim or Charlie Palmer Tub Mill, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 91)
    - Nellie: Tennessee and North Carolina Railroad, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 92)
    - Nellie: Ears Cut Off, 1983-1987 (Box 22, Folder 93)
    - Nellie: Moonshining in Cataloochee Township, 1911-1928, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 94)
    - Nellie: Steel Bridges on NC 284 (built 1928), 1935, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 95)
    - Nellie: Turkey George, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 96)
    - Nellie: Falling Rock Creek, 1970-1983 (Box 22, Folder 97)
    - Nellie: Rough Fork (previously Ugly Fork), undated (Box 22, Folder 98)
    - Nellie: Woody Creek Ridge, undated (Box 22, Folder 99)
    - Nellie: Davidson Gap (3800'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 100)
    - Nellie: Jonathan Woody House (1851), 1974 (Box 22, Folder 101)
    - Nellie: Wolf Bounty, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 102)
    - Nellie: Cataloochee Ranch (1933-1938), 1938, 1987-1993; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 65, Folder 2] (Box 22, Folder 103)
    - Nellie: Wild Man of Cataloochee (Arlie Phillips), 1983-1987 (Box 22, Folder 104)
    - Nellie: Cataloochee CCC Camp 1259, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 105)
    - Nellie: Cherokee Indian Campsite, 1937, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 106)
    - Nellie: Canadian Top (4120'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 107)
    - Nellie: Nellie Ridge (3400'), undated (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - Nellie: Noland Gap (3400'), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - Nellie: Jesse Ridge (3680') named for Jesse R. Palmer, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 110)
    - Nellie: Sal Patch Gap (3600'), 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 111)
    - Nellie: Shanty Branch, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 112)
    - Nellie: Orr Lumber Company, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 113)
    - Nellie: Dude Branch, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 114)
    - Nellie: Pioneer Farmstead (Ocona Luftee), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 115)
    - Nellie: Apple Varieties of Cataloochee Township, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 116)
    - Nellie: Living in National Park after 1930 Impossible, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 117)
    - Nellie: Cataloochee Medical Care Primitive, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 118)
    - Nellie: North Carolina Highway 284, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 119)
    - Nellie: Historic Cataloochee Structures Ordered Burned by Park, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 120)
    - Nellie: Suncrest Lumber Railroad (1925-1929), 1925-2005; (1 of 2) (Box 22, Folder 121)
    - Nellie: Suncrest Lumber Railroad (1925-1929), 1925-2005; (2 of 2) (Box 22, Folder 122)
    - Caldwell Fork: Caldwell Fork (est. 1841), 1937, 1988-1994 (Box 22, Folder 123)
    - Caldwell Fork: Carson Messer Overshot Mill, 1935-1937, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 124)
    - Caldwell Fork: Solomon Sutton Overshot Mill, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 125)
    - Caldwell Fork: Jesse McGee Overshot Mill, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 22, Folder 126)
    - Caldwell Fork: Union Kills Levi Shelton and Ells Caldwell (1863), 1914-1994 (Box 22, Folder 127)
    - Caldwell Fork: Caldwell Fork School (est. 1923), 1923, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 128)
    - Caldwell Fork: Caldwell Fork Baptist Church (est. 1928), 1983 (Box 22, Folder 129)
    - Caldwell Fork: Lucious Caldwell, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 130)
    - Caldwell Fork: Boogerman Trail, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 131)
    - Caldwell Fork: Ferguson Cabin, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 132)
    - Caldwell Fork: McKee (misnamed McGee) Branch Trail, undated (Box 22, Folder 133)
    - Little Catloochee: Ola, NC, 1911-2000 (Box 22, Folder 134)
    - Little Catloochee: Cooks Creek, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 135)
    - Little Catloochee: Little Cataloochee, 1937, 1983-2002 (Box 22, Folder 136)
    - Little Catloochee: Baptist Preacher William M. Hall, undated (Box 22, Folder 137)
    - Little Catloochee: William G. B. Messer House, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 138)
    - Little Catloochee: Mark Hannah (park ranger), 1983-2001 (Box 22, Folder 139)
    - Little Catloochee: Logan Hannah (Confederate Soldier), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Little Catloochee: John Jackson Hannah Cabin, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Little Catloochee: W. J. Hannah, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Little Catloochee: James A. Hannah, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Little Catloochee: William Green Berry Messer, 1983-1988 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Little Catloochee: Daniel J. Cook Cabin, 1983, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Little Catloochee: Steve Waycaster Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Little Catloochee: Tine Woody Tub Mill, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Little Catloochee: Vic Smith, 1937-1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Little Catloochee: Neil Sutton Sugar Mill, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Little Catloochee: Mack Hannah, 1981-1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Little Catloochee: Jim Hannah Cabin, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Little Catloochee: Irving Messer and Mericus Hall Last to Move Away, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Little Catloochee: Woody Branch, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Little Catloochee: Andrew O. Kerr Place, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Little Catloochee: Flora Messer and Charles Morrow Married (1916 November 5), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Little Catloochee: Baptist Church, 1937-2003 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Little Catloochee: Little Catloochee School, 1911-1927, 1983-1988 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Little Catloochee: Cataloochee Indian Trail, 1940, 1983-1988 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Little Catloochee: Cataloochee Turnpike, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Little Catloochee: Cataloochee Stock Road, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Little Catloochee: Jonas (Tobe) Phillips, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Little Catloochee: Hollow Log Camp, undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Little Catloochee: Three-day Trip to Waynesville, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Little Catloochee: Squire Mitchell Sutton, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Little Catloochee: Few Slaves in Cataloochee Township, undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Little Catloochee: Indian Mound, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Bishop Francis Asbury, 1914, 1983-2005 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - McMahon's Grave, 1987-1989 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Hannah Cemetery, 1929, 1983-1987 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Little Cataloochee Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Negro Graveyard ( Slave Cemetery), 1983-1990 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Lawson Jenkins Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Hannah Graveyard, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Palmer Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Palmer Chapel Cemetery, 1983-1987 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Dock Caldwell Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Hiram Caldwell Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Robert Palmer Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Carson Messer, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Sutton & McGee Cemetery, 1987-1989 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Shelton and Caldwell Cemetery, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - D. H. Burress Child Cemetery, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Indian Grave, 1987-1990 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Indian Ridge Cemetery, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Noland Cemetery, undated (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Davidson Slave Cemetery, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Dogwood Cemetery, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Manson Wells Cemetery, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Gap Spring Cemetery, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - Caldwell Indian Cemetery, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Mount Sterling Gap, NC (3890'), 1983-1988 (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - Grooms Family, undated (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - Hanging of Solomon Grooms (1871), 1914, 1961, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - Henry Barns Killed in Kirk's Raid, 1939-1983 (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Sheriff Dawson Murdered, 1982-1989 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - Mount Sterling School, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - Mount Sterling Schools 1 and 2, 1899 (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - Mount Sterling School 3, 1907 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - Mount Sterling Methodist Episcopal Church South, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Pigeon River Dam Revolutionizes Cataloochee Township, 1914-1929, 1983-1987 (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - Sage Sutton Overshot Mill (1928-1952), 1911, 1983-1990 (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - Mount Sterling: A. W. Hopkins Overshot Mill, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - Mount Sterling: Laurel Fork Lumber Company Tram Line, 1896-1928, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - Mount Sterling: Haddock-France Lumber Company Tram Line, 1910-1914, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - Mount Sterling: Laurel Fork Lumber Mount Sterling Tram incline, 2000-2004 (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - Mount Sterling: Haddock-France Lumber Railroad Mount Sterling Tram, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - Mount Sterling: Benjamin Hopkins (1808-1884), undated (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - Mount Sterling: Hopkins Family, 1923-1928, 1974-1983 (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - Mount Sterling: Mount Sterling, NC, Family History, undated (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - Mount Sterling: Walters Hydroelectric Plant, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - Mount Sterling: Crestmont, NC, 1910-2005 (Box 23, Folder 72)
    - Crestmont: Dr. Mac: A Beloved Physician, 1974-1988 (Box 23, Folder 73)
    - Crestmont: 5 Killed in Railroad Accident, 1911-1913, 1988-1994; [Oversized Material Removed to Box 65, Folder 3] (Box 23, Folder 74)
    - Crestmont: Frank Grecco (Railroad Contractor), 1912 (Box 23, Folder 75)
    - Crestmont: Suncrest Lumber Company, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 76)
    - Crestmont: Pigeon River Lumber Company (1906-1911), 2004 (Box 23, Folder 77)
    - Crestmont: The Cataloochee Company Railroad (1902-1906), undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 78)
    - Crestmont: The Cataloochee Company (1902-1906), 1902-1904 (Box 23, Folder 79)
    - Crestmont: Crestmont School (1911-1918), 1911, 1974, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 80)
    - Crestmont: CCC Camp Zeb Weaver (415), undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 81)
    - Crestmont: Dr. J. Walter McMahan, 1914, 1957-2004 (Box 23, Folder 82)
    - Crestmont: Tennessee & North Carolina Railroad, 1903-2004 (Box 23, Folder 83)
    - Crestmont: CCC Camp Zeb Weaver (415), 1933-1935, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 84)
    - Crestmont: Dr. J. A. P. Shields, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 85)
    - Crestmont: Crestmont Sunday School (est. 1902), undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 86)
    - Crestmont: Crestmont Church (1911-1918), 1914 (Box 23, Folder 87)
    - Crestmont: Champion Skidder Left on Big Creek, undated (Box 23, Folder 88)
    - Crestmont: Dynamite Explosion Kills Six (1906 December 15), [Oversized Material Removed to Box 65, Folder 4] (Box 23, Folder 89)
    - Crestmont: Mount Sterling (5835'), 1983-1995 (Box 23, Folder 90)
    - Crestmont: Mount Sterling Community, 1903-1929, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 91)
    - Crestmont: Big Creek, 1953, 1994; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 65, Folder 5] (Box 23, Folder 92)
    - Crestmont: Began as Lumber Town, 1911-1913 (Box 23, Folder 93)
    - Crestmont: Crestmont Incorporated (1913), 1913, 1994-1996 (Box 23, Folder 94)
    - Crestmont: Robert F. Whitmere, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 95)
    - Crestmont: North Carolina Land & Lumber Company (est. 1900), undated (Box 23, Folder 96)
    - Crestmont: Incline for Champion Lumber Company, undated (Box 23, Folder 97)
    - Crestmont: The Champion Lumber Company, 1911-1918, 1995, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 98)
    - Crestmont: Pigeon River Lumber Company (1906-1911) (Box 23, Folder 99)
    - Crestmont: Champion Lumber Company (1911-1917), 1913, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 100)
    - Crestmont: Transcontinental Railroad Begins Work Near Waterville, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 101)
    - Crestmont: Suncrest Buys Champion (1918 August 10), 1913, 1928, 1993-1995 (Box 23, Folder 102)
    - Crestmont: Writing on Rocks at Big Creek, undated (Box 23, Folder 103)
    - Crestmont: Andrew McMahan Killed by Engine, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 104)
    - Crestmont: Champion International Corporation, 1907-1939, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 105)
    - Crestmont: Chestnut Branch, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 106)
    - Crestmont: Presbyterian Mission School (1920-1934), 1935, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 107)
    - Crestmont: Tennessee & Southeastern Railway, 1917 (Box 23, Folder 108)
    - Crestmont: Rail Grade Made into Highway, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 109)
    - Crestmont: Mount Sterling School (Chestnut Branch), 1934 (Box 23, Folder 110)
    - Crestmont: Hungry Hollow, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 111)
    - Walnut Bottom: Big Creek Tulip Poplar, undated (Box 23, Folder 112)
    - Walnut Bottom: Logging Camp, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 113)
    - Walnut Bottom: Logging Town, undated; [Folder Found Empty] (Box 23, Folder 114)
    - Walnut Bottom: Mouse Creek Falls, 1911, 1973-2003 (Box 23, Folder 115)
    - Walnut Bottom: Jim Wiggins Killed Dynamite Fishing, 1911, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 116)
    - Walnut Bottom: Bear Creek Incline Railroad, 1912-1995 (Box 23, Folder 117)
    - Walnut Bottom: Swallow Fork Camp, undated (Box 23, Folder 118)
    - Walnut Bottom: Gunter Fork Camp, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 119)
    - Walnut Bottom: George Gunter, 1928 (Box 23, Folder 120)
    - Walnut Bottom: Yellow Creek Camp, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 121)
    - Walnut Bottom: Mount Guyot Camp, undated (Box 23, Folder 122)
    - Walnut Bottom: Camel Hump Knob Camp, undated (Box 23, Folder 123)
    - Walnut Bottom: Ross Knob (5040'), undated (Box 23, Folder 124)
    - Davenport Gap: Davenport Gap, 1914-1996 (Box 23, Folder 125)
    - Davenport Gap: Walnut Bottoms Cemetery, 1987-1991 (Box 23, Folder 126)
    - Davenport Gap: Hillard McGaha Cemetery, 1943-1945, 1987-1995 (Box 23, Folder 127)
    - Davenport Gap: Henry Barnes, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 128)
    - Davenport Gap: Hopkins Cemetery, 1923-1928, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 129)
    - Davenport Gap: Yellow Creek Camp Cemetery, undated (Box 23, Folder 130)
    - Davenport Gap: Garfield Jenkins Cemetery, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 131)
    - Davenport Gap: Carolina, Knoxville & Western Railway, 1888; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 65, Folder 6] (Box 23, Folder 132)
    - Davenport Gap: Pigeon River Railroad, 1907-1928 (Box 23, Folder 133)
    - Davenport Gap: Mount Cammerer (4928'), 1911, 1955, 1989-2000; [Oversized Materials Removed to Box 65, Folder 7] (Box 23, Folder 134)
    - Davenport Gap: Arno B. Cammerer, 1937-1941, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 135)
    - Davenport Gap: County Line CCC Camp, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 136)
    - Davenport Gap: Indian Camp Creek CCC Side Camp, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Davenport Gap: Maddron Bald CCC Side Camp, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Davenport Gap: Mount Guyot CCC Side Camp, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)